This afternoon, we're going to look a little bit at the development of the skull.
今日の午後、頭蓋骨の発達について少し見ていきます。
This time, we're going to add the meninges around it.
今回は、その周りに髄膜を追加します。
We're going to add the development of the vault and of
頭蓋冠と頭蓋底の
the base of the skull.
発達を追加します。
The base of the skull, the vault, starting from this movement of brain development,
頭蓋底、頭蓋冠、脳の発達のこの動きから、
we're going to see that there's a whole logic, an almost logical sequence, of information
情報と構築の論理的な連続性があることがわかります。
we're going to see a little bit how it happens
それがどのように起こるか少し見ていきます。
and how we can also put that in our hands
そして、それをどのように手で感じることができるか。
and how, in a way,
そして、どういうわけか、
to understand that the engine
その原動力は、
for this development is
この発達の原動力は、
the differentiated growth rate
分化成長の速度であると理解することです。
not bad
悪くない。
but for the skull, it's the brain
しかし、頭蓋骨にとっては脳です。
what we saw yesterday
昨日見たように、
you saw this kind of development
あなたはこの種の発達を見ました。
this somewhat extraordinary movement of the brain
脳のこの少し並外れた動きを。
like that, you see, with this phase there
このように、その段階で、
of doing
行うこと。
at a given moment, of cerebralization with all the straightening of
ある時点で、脳化の段階があり、それに伴い、胚の全体的な直立化が起こり、
the embryo that follows with all this force that manages to
胚の全体的な直立化が起こり、そのすべての力が前正中線に再集中しようとします。
recenter towards the anterior median line,
前正中線に再集中しようとします。
which is ultimately a median line of anticipation. It's a line where you have the whole process
それは最終的に予測の正中線です。それは、生殖腺形成の全プロセスがある線です。つまり、あなたは生殖することができ、すべての究極のプロセスをやり直すことができます。
of gonadization, so you can reproduce, you can redo everything that is the ultimate process
生殖腺形成の全プロセスがある線です。つまり、あなたは生殖することができ、すべての究極のプロセスをやり直すことができます。
with the sternum, so your immunity.
外部、つまりあなたの免疫力とともに。
which goes forward, so it's a whole
前方に進むので、それは全体的な
scheme that can give you back
あなたにあなたの予測を
your anticipation. Sometimes you have
取り戻すことができる図式です。あなたは時々、
quite a few people who are blocked.
多くの人々がブロックされています。
There are some people I've come to, I've pressed
私が来た人の中には、私が時々、
sometimes, maybe on one or two places,
おそらく1つか2つの場所で、
to open up the spaces of time a bit.
時間の空間を少し開くために、押した人がいます。
Sometimes, we close ourselves off to
時々、私たちはこの瞬間に閉じこもってしまい、
this immediate, and you have like
この瞬間に閉じこもってしまい、
micro-crystals
微細な結晶のようなものがあります。
It's as if it were concentrated time
それは集中した時間のようなもので、
that needs to be released, because you no longer know how to
解放されなければなりません。なぜなら、あなたはもはや
anticipate. You stay there a bit.
予測することができないからです。あなたはそこに少し留まっています。
You remain as if held in an old thing that no longer exists.
あなたはもはや存在しない古いものの中に閉じ込められているように留まっています。
Sometimes, there are quite a few people like that who live in the past.
時々、過去に生きている人がたくさんいます。
From time to time, I give an image like that to make it a bit stronger.
時々、私はもっと強くするために、このようなイメージを与えます。
I tell them, "Look, it's as if in your pocket, you had a small vial from the past."
私は彼らに言います、「ほら、まるでポケットの中に過去から来た小さな小瓶を持っているようなものだ」と。
In which you introduced a bad smell.
その中に、あなたは悪臭を閉じ込めた。
A really bad smell.
本当にひどい悪臭を。
And every day, you see, you smell this bad odor.
そして毎日、ほら、あなたはその悪臭を感じる。
I say, "But let it open, let it go."
私は言います、「でも、開けて、手放して」と。
Anyway, that's how it is.
とにかく、そういうものだ。
But that's when you accept death.
しかし、それはあなたが死を受け入れるときだ。
When you understand death, all of a sudden, you become cooler with your own
死を理解すると、突然、あなたは自分自身の時間に対してより冷静になる。
time.
時間。
Suddenly, you remember the essential.
突然、あなたは本質を思い出す。
But for that, you first need to study the Bardot processes.
しかし、そのためには、まずバルドーのプロセスを研究する必要がある。
That means you really have to go into that state where you can easily free yourself
それは、まさにこれらのパターンから簡単に解放されることができる状態に、本当に行く必要があることを意味する。
from these patterns.
パターンから簡単に解放されることができる状態に、本当に行く必要があることを意味する。
Embryology and then the processes of death.
発生学、そして死のプロセス。
Ultimately, how do we get there?
最終的に、どうやってたどり着くのか？
How do we pass?
どうやって通過するのか？
I think that with each breath,
私は、呼吸をするたびに、
we pass through the time of creation.
創造の時を通過していると思います。
With each breath, you do that.
呼吸をするたびに、あなたはそれをする。
That's where, precisely,
まさにそこで、
you perceive that you can
あなたは自分が
precisely catch your breath each time
まさに毎回息を吹き返すことができると認識する。
and that you are invited to be
そして、あなたは招かれている。
in this moment of transformation.
この変容の瞬間に。
Everything that rises,
立ち上がるすべてのものは、
is to accept letting it go.
それを手放すことを受け入れることだ。
It's always hard.
それはいつも辛い。
What is it about me
私の中に何があるのか
that is so afraid of dying? What have I acquired, ultimately, throughout my life, that makes me
死ぬのがそんなに怖いのか。結局、私の人生を通して何を得たのか、それが死に直面したときに私をこのようにさせるのか。
like this in the face of death?
死に直面したときに、私はこのようにさせるのか。
And often, it's all these brakes that are there, and in fact, don't worry.
そして、多くの場合、そこにあるのはこれらのすべてのブレーキであり、実際、心配しないでください。
That's where you have to give confidence in a word, you see. That's where you have to let this word emerge
そこでは、言葉に信頼を与える必要がある、ほら。そこでは、その言葉を出現させ、
and be able to give this word, this gesture or this look to the person to give them
そして、その言葉、そのジェスチャー、またはその視線をその人に与えて、彼らに
this path of...
この声を与える必要がある。
It's about trust.
それは信頼だ。